Essex Company Photographs 6633 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- P 217.52-.63, .65-.71, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: Flood of 1896, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Interior view of Lower Pacific Mills Combing Room
  - Item 18: Flood of 1896, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Interior view of Lower Pacific Mills Card Room
  - Item 19: Flood of 1896, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 1)
- P 217.48-.51, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
    W. F. Cutler's Residence, 176 Salem St., So. Lawrence, before and after cyclone July 26, 1890
  - Item 2: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
    A North Andover house.
  - Item 3: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Lawrence tornado of 1890.
  - Item 4: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Springfield Street.
- P 217.16-.32, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking southwesterly from near the east end of Springfield Street.
  - Item 2: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking from the south side of Springfield St. near Foster St. northeasterly along the north side of Springfield St.
  - Item 3: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking northeasterly into the Park from near Union St.
  - Item 4: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking westerly from near northeast corner of the Park.
  - Item 5: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking north of east nearly the whole length of houses on the south side of Springfield St.
  - Item 8: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking northerly to near the east end of Springfield St.
  - Item 9: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking from the north side of Springfield St. southerly near its west end.
  - Item 10: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking southeasterly from north side of Springfield St. near its east end.
  - Item 11: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking from near the east end of Springfield St. southeasterly.
  - Item 12: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking from north side of Springfield St. southwesterly, near its easterly end.
  - Item 13: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    House on Market St. near Union St. Looking southwesterly. This house was on the southern limit of disturbance and was moved westerly eight feet.
  - Item 14: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    View of damage.
  - Item 15: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking northeasterly to near the westerly end of Springfield St.
  - Item 16: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking northeasterly to the back side of houses on the south side of Springfield St. near its middle section, west of Foster St.
  - Item 17: Lawrence tornado of 1890., black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Looking southerly from north side of Springfield St. near its west end.
- P 217.33, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Connecticut River at Brattleboro, VT., 1869; black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 4)
    High water in 1869 previous to the building of Yernon Dam.
- P 217.34-.35, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Connecticut River at Brattleboro, VT., 1869; black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 5)
    High water in 1869 after the building of Yernon Dam.
  - Item 2: Break in Canal Bank, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 5)
    March 20, 1907.
- P 217.545, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Merrimac Paper Company, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Merrimac(k) Paper Company's coating mill, Lawrence, Mass.
- P 217.43-.44, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Photographs of unidentified canal being excavated (stamp on reverse indicates that photographer is from Nashua, N.H.)
  - Item 2: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 7)
- P 217.41-.42, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 8)
- P 217.45-.47, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 9)
- P 217.36-.40, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 3: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 4: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 5: Canal Excavation, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 10)
- P 217.551-.552, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Robert H. Tewksbury, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Mayor of Lawrence (1875) and employee of Essex Co.
  - Item 2: Essex Company Office, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Essex Company office, Lawrence, Mass., ca. 1915
- P 2001.112- .1-.3, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Essex Company house, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Albumen print of Essex Company House, ca. 1890. Copy 1
  - Item 2: Essex Company house, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Albumen print of Essex Company House, ca. 1890. Copy 2
  - Item 3: Essex Company house, black and white photograph (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Albumen print of Essex Company House, ca. 1890. Copy 3
- P 217 - .544-.550, P 217.614, P 217.615, P 1245.2, P 1245.3, P 198.9, black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Pemberton Mills, Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Photographed by Fred M. Smith, 27 Tremont Row,Boston, Mass. Gelatin silver print, ca. 1880. Image depicts the Pemberton Mills in Lawrence, Mass., showing six-story brick building with two fire escapes; the word Pemberton is in stone on the short side of the building on the right. A railroad car and railroad tracks are on the right next to the canal. Building is surrounded by other brick mill buildings; the old Washington Mills can be seen on the far right. This would be the mill built after the collapse of the prior Pemberton Mill in January 1860. 33.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 2: North Canal, 1902, black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    No. 2 Essex Company North Canal [Lawrence] July 27, 1902. View looking upstream showing general arrangement of enlarging mouth pieces at sluiceways, entrance to canal. Surface of water at about (20.5)
  - Item 3: Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Lawrence Dam looking north.
  - Item 4: Great freshet of April 1852, black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    View reversed. Lawrence?
  - Item 5: Longfellow Bridge, Boston, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Whitney & Son, Cambridge [Mass.] photographer. Gelatin silver print, [after 1906]. Image depicts the Longfellow Bridge, connecting Boston to Cambridge, Mass., from the Boston side. The bridge was known as the Cambridge Bridge until 1927 when it was renamed the Longfellow Bridge. 24.25 x 18.5 cm. (w/out mount); 35 x 27.25 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 6: Den Rock, black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Den Rock, Lawrence, Mass.
  - Item 7: Hood School, Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Alma mater of Dr. R.J. Hyde, Esq.
  - Item 8: View of Essex Company Dam, Lawrence, Mass., 1905; black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image depicts frozen falls at the Essex Company dam in Lawrence, Mass., March 3, 1905. Image actually made of two prints joined together. See Item 9, in this folder, for a better print taken at a slightly different angle. 29.25 x 11 cm. (w/out mount); 40.5 x 22 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 9: View of Essex Company Dam, Lawrence, Mass., 1905; black and white photograph (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image depicts frozen falls at the Essex Company dam in Lawrence, Mass., March 3, 1905. Image actually made of two prints joined together. See Item 8, in this folder, for another print (not as clear) taken at a slightly different angle. 30 x 11 cm. (w/out mount); 40.5 x 21.5 cm. (w/mount).
- Photo Album of pictures of bridges near textile mills, black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Album of Lawrence photographs, black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Various views of North and South Canal, dam, bridges, canals, locks, penstocks, rails, etc.
- Photo album of pictures of textile mills, black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Album of Lawrence photographs, black and white photograph (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Atlantic Mills, Washington Mills, Pacific Mills, Plymouth Mills, Kunhardt, Lawrence Duck. Everett, Russell, Munroe, Lawrence Gas, South Canal.
- P 217.481-.519 -- Walter E. Smear (1892); Charles S. Storrow; Holyoke Water Power Co.; Washington Mills Storehouse; Lawrence Mills; Arlington Mills; North Canal; Merrimack River; Pacific Mills, 1892-1908 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: View of Holyoke Water Power Company Canal Fencing, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: View of Holyoke Water Power Company Canal Fencing, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Tenement house property adjoining canal.
  - Item 4: View of Holyoke Water Power Company Canal Fencing, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Public highway bordering on canal.
  - Item 5: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    View from Lower Pacific Mill No. 4, Merrimack River, Lawrence.
  - Item 8: View in rear of Pacific Mills, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    At Race #1 from South side of River, Nov. 12, 1908
  - Item 9: View in rear of Pacific Mills, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    From South side of River, Nov. 12, 1908
  - Item 10: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    View of rear of Lower Pacific Mills.
  - Item 11: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    View of B & M R.R. Bridge, Lawrence.
  - Item 12: View of Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Mills in background
  - Item 13: View in rear of Pacific Mills, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    From South side of River
  - Item 14: View of Pacfic Mills from Dam, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    April 17, 1895.
  - Item 15: View of Pacfic Mills from Dam, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    November 12, 1908.
  - Item 16: View of Bottom of Merrimack River, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    July 9, 1911.
  - Item 17: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: View of North Andover Mills, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 19: View looking down Canal, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    From Pacific R.R. Bridge, Canal Street on the left, June 1897
  - Item 20: View of Broadway Bridge over Canal, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    From point near Essex Co's Gate House, June 1897
  - Item 21: View of Arlington Mills, Lawrence, MA, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 22: View of Lawrence Mills, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 23: View of Lawrence Mills, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 24: View of Pacific Mills, Lawrence, MA, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 25: View of Washington Mills store house, 1890; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Alos Pemberton Mills store house, July 1890
  - Item 26: View of unidentified man playing golf, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 27: Group of Essex Company employees, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Albumen print, ca. 1878. Image depicts a posed group of men, most of whom (probably all) were employed by the Essex Company of Lawrence, Mass. Identified on reverse: front row, left to right: C. W. Kempton, Fred Chabot, Nelson Harris, and Thomas Holmes; back row, left to right: Fred Whittier, C. J. O'Reilly, Richard A. Hale, and James O'Reilly. In the 1877 Lawrence, Mass., directory, James L. O'Reilly, Whittier, and Hale were all listed as students at the Essex Company, while Fred Chabot was listed as an assistant, and Holmes as a gate tender. By 1881, Hale and Whittier had joined Chabot as assistants, while Holmes remained a gate tender. All of the men wear dark suits with wide lapels, white shirts, and dark ties (except for James O'Reilly and Holmes, who wear light ties). Several wear dark overcoats. Hale (1852-1928) wears pince nez, the ony one in the group wearing spectacles of any kind; he eventually became chief engineer of the Essex Company in 1921. Most of the men have mustaches; Holmes has a beard. 23 x 18 cm. (w/out mount); 24.25 x 19.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 28: Cabinet card photo of Charles S. Storrow, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 29: Cabinet card photo of Walter E. Spear, L.H.S., 1892; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 30: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 31: View of children playing at water pump, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 32: View of children playing at water pump, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 33: View of children playing at water pump, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 34: Family group photo, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 35: View of Essex Company Dam, Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
    View of children in boat fishing
  - Item 36: Family group photo, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 37: Family group photo, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 38: Family group photo, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Item 39: Family group photo, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 1)
- P 217.438-.480 -- North Canal, Lawrence, Mass.; Lawrence Dam; Pawtucket Falls, 1892-1925 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: View of Lower End of North Canal, 1887; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Spillway. August 1887.
  - Item 2: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: View of men repairing flash boards on dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: View of men repairing flash boards on dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: View of men repairing flash boards on dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: View of men repairing flash boards on dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: View of scow used to repair flash boards at top of Lawrence Dam, Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Gelatin silver contact print, [197-?; original glass plate negative ca.1905-10?]. Image depicts a scow used on the Merrimack River to repair the flashboards at the top of the Lawrence Dam (formally known as the Merrimack River Dam) in Lawrence, Mass. Several factory chimneys and other buildings visible on the far side of the river in the background. At least eight men are on the scow, some holding sledgehammers; see Item 8, in this folder, for another view of this scow. Unclear when the contact print was made, but the original image dates from approximately 1905-1910. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 8: Scow used to repair flash boards at top of Lawrence Dam with laborers, Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Gelatin silver contact print, [197-?; original glass plate negative ca.1905-10?]. Image depicts a scow used on the Merrimack River to repair the flashboards at the top of the Lawrence Dam (formally known as the Merrimack River Dam) in Lawrence, Mass. Buildings visible on the far side of the river in the background. A dozen men are on the scow, some holding sledgehammers; see Item 7, in this folder, for another view of this scow. Unclear when the contact print was made, but the original image dates from approximately 1905-1910. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 9: View in freshet, 1892, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: View of Lawrence Dam, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    April 16th, 1909, Pond Gauge=42.12. Depth on stonecrest=8 ft.
  - Item 14: View of Lawrence Dam, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    South end, April 1896
  - Item 15: Freshet of April 1895, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    View of Lawrence Dam, South end at time of freshet, April 1895, fishway submerged
  - Item 16: Freshet of April 1895, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    View of Lawrence Dam
  - Item 17: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 18: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 19: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    View of water on Lawrence Dam
  - Item 20: Freshet of March 1896, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    During spring freshet
  - Item 21: View of Lawrence Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    April 16th, 1909. Pond Gauge=42.12. Depth on stone crest=8 ft.
  - Item 22: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Fish ladder
  - Item 23: View of Lawrence Dam, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    In freshet
  - Item 24: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 25: View of Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 26: View of Lawrence Dam, 1893; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    High Water
  - Item 27: View of Lawrence Dam, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Looking South
  - Item 28: View of Lawrence Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    April 16th, 1909. Pond Gauge=42.12. Depth on stone crest-8 ft.
  - Item 29: View of Lawrence Dam, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Flashboards broken
  - Item 30: View of Lawrence Dam, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 31: View of Lawrence Dam, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 32: View showing breaking ice on North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 33: View of ice on Lawrence Dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 34: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 35: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 36: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 37: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 38: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 39: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 40: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 41: View of ice on North Canal, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Item 42: View of Pawtucket Falls, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Lowell, MA, High Water
- P 217.616-.635 -- Pacific Mills (ca. 1880); South end Pond Gauge (April 16, 1909); Pawtucket Falls (Apr. 9, 1901); frozen dam photos; Freshet (Mar. 2, 1896) - misc. unlabeled photos, 1880-1909 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Lawrence, MA, April 16, 1909, from near South end
  - Item 2: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Lawrence, MA, ca. 1909
  - Item 4: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 13: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 14: View of Boston and Maine R.R. Bridge, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Looking North when Lower Pacific River Gauge=28.50. Freshet March 2, 1896, 1.40 P.M.
  - Item 15: View of Pacific Mills [upper site], black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
    ca. 1880, before Weave Shed built surrounding chimney - 1882
  - Item 16: View of Bay State/Washington Mill, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Looking East along North Canal, Pemberton at left rear
  - Item 17: View of Merrimack River and Mills, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Item 18: View of Merrimack River and Mills, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 3)
- P 217.604-.612 -- Photos of frozen waterfall, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Lawrence, MA, March 3, 1905 (frozen falls)
  - Item 2: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)